<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="36"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[苏国外希雅国际学校














































       Welcome to




      Suzhou




      Innovation




      Academy






      欢迎来到苏国外希雅国际学校





        领 创 美 好 生 活

        L E A D I N G  A  P R O S P E R O U S  L I F E                                                   2023]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[纳新融变  筑梦未来


                         Inspiring learners to become architects of their future
















































      1]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[苏国外希雅国际学校






































         目录


          CONTENT




                   源自姑苏 跨世纪卓越学校
          01       A Cross-Century School of
                   Excellence in Suzhou



          02       中国基因 领创美好生活                                06       希雅为基石 通往世界名校之路
                                                                       SIA the Roadmap to
                   An International Education Built
                   on a Chinese Foundation                             World-Famous Universities

                   卓越团队 支持学生蓬勃发展                                       专业升学团队 打造专属升学方案
          03       Academic Programme                         07       Professional Counsellors

                   Supporting Learners to Flourish
                   Today and Tomorrow                                  Create an Exclusive Admission Scheme

                   卓越课程 激发创新才能                                         多维关怀 助力学生成长
          04       Excellent Curriculums                      08       Multi-Dimensional Care
                   fulfilling our talent together                      to Help Students Grow


                   终身学习成长 希雅师生如是说                                      跨世纪老牌名校 森林氧吧
          05       Lifelong Learning of                       09       Cross-century brand school with
                   SIA Teachers and Students
                                                                       Natural forest setting

                                                              10       加入我们 筑梦未来
                                                                       Join Us and Become Architects of
                                                                       Your Own Future

                                                                                                                  2]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[01                                                   办学使命


                                                                 School Mission


                                                                  苏国外希雅国际学校旨在博采中西方教育理念
                                  源自姑苏                       的精粹，培养美好生活的领创者；成为内蕴卓越中
                                                             国基因的IB学校（全球代码：003908）；立志为中

                     跨世纪卓越学校                                 国国际教育做出卓越贡献。苏国外创办于1995年，
                                                             畔阳澄湖，隶属于启迪教育集团，从幼儿园到高中
                A Cross-Century School of                    十五年一贯制，是华东地区历史最悠久的著名国际
                                                             化学校之一。
                   Excellence from Suzhou
                                                             Suzhou  Innovation  Academy  Suzhou  Innovation  Academy
                                                             aims to draw on the quintessence of Chinese and Western
                                                             educational  concepts  to  cultivate  leaders  of  a  prosperous
                                                             life, and to become an IB world school. Suzhou Innovation
                                                             Academy(Global  code:  003908)  is  a  highly  ranked  IB
                                                             diploma school dedicated to cultivating talents in this fast-
                                                             changing,  dynamic  century.  Suzhou  International  Foreign
                                                             Language School was founded in 1995 in Suzhou, located by
                                                             Yangcheng  Lake.  It  is  affiliated  to  SIFLS  Qidi  Education
                                                             Group.  SIFLS  is  one  of  the  most  famous  and  oldest
                                                             international  schools  in  East  China  and  is  the  first
                                                             nationally renowned K-12 private school in Suzhou..













      3]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[苏国外希雅国际学校











               苏国外希雅国际学校以极高质量的两年制国际文凭组织大学预科课程(IBDP)和一年制预备课程（FP），为
          学生提供多元文化环境和创新、挑战的教育体验。
               我们致力于培养学生杰出的学术能力，坚韧的成长心态和卓越的创新精神，以进入全球Top30名校为开
          端，成为具有强烈的责任感和使命感的世界公民。
          Suzhou  Innovation  Academy  offers  the  internationally  renowned  2-year  IB  Diploma  Program  (IBDP)  and  a  one-year
          Foundation Program(FP). Students will receive an exciting and challenging multicultural education at SIA.
          Starting  from  entering  the  top  30  universities  in  the  world,  SIA  graduates  will  become  excellent  global  citizens  with
          outstanding Chinese genes because of their outstanding knowledge, perseverance, and unswerving enthusiasm for learning.


































                   价值观
                   Values



               我们鼓励每一位学校成员践行以下价值标准：



                                  理 解                    共 情                    幸 福

                              Understanding              Empathy               Happiness



                                  贡 献                  耐 挫 力                  真 善 美
                                Selﬂessness            Perseverance           Truthfulness







                                                                                                                  4]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[发展历程

                   Founding History





















                                                                                2008年


                                                                                苏国外开办澳大利亚维多利亚州高
                                                                                中课程项目；
                                                                                In 2008, Suzhou International Foreign
                                                                                L a n g u a g e  S c h o o l  l a u n c h e d  i t s
                                                                                Australian  Victoria  Certificate  of
                                                                                Education high-school programme.
                  1995年

                  苏国外创办于中国苏州·阳澄湖畔；
                  In 1995, Suzhou International Foreign
                  Language  School  was  founded  by
                  Yangcheng Lake in Suzhou, China.





                                                           1999年

                                                            苏国外踏出国际教育第一步，开办
                                                            国际项目；
                                                            In  1999,  Suzhou  International  Foreign
                                                            Language School launched international
                                                            programs.



















      5]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[苏国外希雅国际学校







                                                                             2022年

                                                                             希雅首届毕业生100%进入全球排
                                                                             名前50的大学或排名前30的专业深
                                                                             造，实现创校梦想。
                                                                             In  2022,  100%  of  SIA s  first  graduates

          2014年                                                              have entered top 50 universities in the
                                                                             world or the top 30 majors for further
          苏国外希雅国际学校成为国际文凭                                                    s t u d y,  r e a l i z i n g  o u r  f o u n d i n g
          组织大学预科项目（IBDP）候选                                                   objectives.
          学校；同年开设美高项目；
          In 2014, Suzhou International Foreign
          Language  School  became  a  candidate
          s c h o o l   f o r   t h e   I n t e r n a t i o n a l
          Baccalaureate  Diploma  Programme
          (IBDP); in the same year, the American
          High School Program was established.





                                                                   2021年

                    2019年                                          苏国外开办A Level项目；

                    苏国外希雅国际学校通过国际文凭                                In  2021,  the  A-Level  programme  was
                    组织授权，正式成为IB世界学校；                               launched  at  Suzhou  International
                    In  2019,  Suzhou  Innovation  Academy         Foreign Language School.
                    officially  became  an  IB  World  School
                    through  the  authorization  of  the
                    I n t e r n a t i o n a l   B a c c a l a u r e a t e
                    Organization.





























                                                                                                                  6]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[02










                                                     中国基因


                                            领创美好生活


                                  An International Education
                              Built on a Chinese Foundation











           “立志、立行、立业” 和 “兼济天下”

           Chinese-nurtured Talents to Lead a Better life

               源远流长、博大精深的中国文化和精神对教育的影响上溯两千多年。在希雅，学习扎根于中国基因，放眼于
          世界未来，学生胸怀 “立志、立行、立业”和“兼济天下”的信念。身体力行价值追求，爱国敬业、孝亲尊师、
          重友优学、开拓未来。在青少年成长最关键的时期形成自己的独立人格，是受益终生的宝贵经历。希雅学生将满
          怀自信走向世界，在多元文化中游刃有余，又能回归祖国大展宏图。

          The influence of the long-standing and profound Chinese culture and spirit on education dates back more than two thousand
          years. In the international school of SIA, learning is rooted in Chinese foundation and looks to the future of the world. Students
          have  the  beliefs  of  "  to  build  doctrine,  to  sign  virtue,  to  set  profession   and   contributing  to  the  world ,  practice  the  moral
          principles of "benevolence, righteousness, propriety, wisdom, and trustworthiness , love the motherland, respect for teachers.
          Helping  students  form  their  own  personalities  during  the  most  critical  period  of  time  and  gain  valuable  experience  that  will
          benefit them throughout their lives. SIA students will go into the world with confidence, be able to handle multiple cultures with
          ease, and return to the motherland to make great achievements.





      7]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[希雅将中国历史、政治和文化等国学课程贯穿在各年级IB课纲中，开设“致良知”卓越中国文化课程和国际
         理解课程。在全球化视角下培养学生对中国文化的热爱和对中国身份的认同。在希雅，无论是学习和生活社区，
         通过丰富多彩的社团活动和服务项目，同学们将尊重他人，严谨求学，和而不同，内化为行动力，在多变的世界
         里怀抱良知与勇气。

         SIA integrates Chinese history, politics, and culture and other national courses into the IB curriculum of each grade, integrates
         virtue and festival education into students' daily activities, and cultivates students' passion for Chinese culture and recognition of
         Chinese identity from a global perspective. Whether it is in the study and living community of SIA boarding school or through a
         variety of club activities and service projects, students can study rigorously, know how to care for others, understand harmony in
         diversity, and strive to do things without arguing. Embracing conscience and courage in a changing world.









                                                                                                                  8]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[“致良知” 和 “知行合一”

                                             The Extension of Innake Knowledge &
                                             Unity of Knowledge and Practice


                                                学生通过希雅“创造、活动与服务”的体验式学习，理解希雅始终秉
                                           承的“致良知”和“知行合一”教育理念，学习知识、领会真理更要实践
                                           良知，实现教育的本质追求：求真、扬善、唯美。“纸上得来终觉浅，绝
                                           知此事要躬行”，希雅学生有服务公众的意识，乐于将所学所得回馈社
                                           会，如在社区做义工，帮助多地受灾的群众，在线支教贫困地区，甚至竞
                                           选校长参与创建教学点等，都是对“优学”、“学而时习之，不亦乐乎”
                                           的最好诠释。为使命而学习，为建设更加美好的社区和世界而学习，是希
                                           雅对学生的期待。











                                                                                          纸上得来终觉浅

                                                                                          绝知此事要躬行






                                           知行活动：学会做人

















                                           社群讨论：学会求知













                                                                                    扬帆起航 · 勇敢无畏


      9]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[苏国外希雅国际学校

















                      Through  the  experiential  learning  of  "creativity,  activity,  and  service,"  students  understand  SIA's
                      educational philosophy of "The Extension of Innate Knowledge" and "unity of knowledge and practice"
                      that SIA has always adhered to. To learn knowledge and understand the truth, it is necessary to practice it
                      and realize the essential pursuits of education: seek the truth, promote goodness, and follow satisfaction.
                      SIA students have the sense of public service and are willing to give back to society what they have gained,
                      such as by doing volunteer work, aiding areas suffering from disasters, supporting education in poverty-
                      stricken areas online, and even running for the principal to participate in the establishment of teaching
                      sites.  Learning  with  missions,  learning  for  constructing  a  better  community  and  world.  It  is  a  noble
                      aspiration, and it is also SIA's expectation for students











                                   共创美好社区







                                                                                学院活动：学会共处
































          浓情中秋 · 情系希雅 · 难忘恩师


                                                                                                                  10]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[03                  卓越团队

                              支持学生蓬勃发展

                              Academic Programme Supporting Learners to

                              Flourish Today and Tomorrow






           学术专家委员会

           Academic
           Steering
           Committee







                                               王俊鹏                                            金海清

                                           Wang Junpeng                                     Jin Haiqing
                                         苏州国裕外语学校  校长                                 苏国外启迪教育集团  总校长

                                           著名教育、管理专家                                      著名教育、管理专家
                                         曾任泰州市教育局副局长                                    曾任南通市教育局副局长
                                         江苏省中学物理特级教师                                          省政府督学
                                             教授级高级教师                                       课程教学改革专家
                                       现为江苏省物理学会常务理事                                苏州市基础教育高质量发展首批专家
                                     南京航空航天大学兼职硕士生导师                             江苏省教育学会情景教育专家委员会理事长
                                 南京师范大学物理科学与技术学院兼职研究员





















                                               王嘉鹏                                         克里斯蒂安

                                             Mark Wang                                  Christian Hodeige
                                         中国常熟世界联合学院                                           德国UWC
                                            创始人、董事长                            罗伯特博世学院董事会创始成员、现任主席
                                      第十三届全国人民代表大会代表                                Baden地区日报首席执行官、合伙人
                                       世界联合学院国际理事会理事                          世界联合学院德国委员会会长（1992年-1998年）
                                            中国理事会理事长                          世界联合学院国际会员会主席（1999年-2006年）


      11]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[苏国外希雅国际学校



                   校长团队            Principal Team























                         罗伯特·克劳伦斯                                                  刘乘瑞

                            Robert Clarence                                        Eric Liu
                       苏国外希雅国际学校  创校校长                                   苏国外希雅国际学校  执行校长
                                                                              （学校创始人之一）

                        牛津大学 罗德学者&文学硕士学位                                     苏州市优秀德育工作者；
                          （中世纪英语语言的发展）；                                   十一年国际高中课程管理经验，
                   2014-2018 中国常熟世界联合学院 创校校长；                              先后担任苏国外国际部主任、
                    2018-2020 苏国外希雅国际学校 创校校长。                           苏国外希雅国际IBDP协调员等职务；
                                                                          多次赴国外访问、交流、培训，
                                                                     获多项国际文凭组织和国家级专业资格认证。











                   师资团队 Faculty Team



                  全球甄选满怀激情、超一流的教学及管理人员组成领导团队。该团队打造优质教学框架和学术结构，
             并已构建一支卓越的教师队伍，共同培养卓越中国基因的世界公民。中外师资比为1:1。
                  我们的团队包括：专业外教、海归、博士、硕士、IB考官、IB评估小组成员，其中包括多名从事IB教
             育十年以上的经验丰富的优秀教师。

             Our leadership team is composed of passionate and experienced teaching & management staff from around the world. The
             team has built an excellent team of teachers, with a high-quality teaching framework and academic structure, to cultivate
             world citizens with an outstanding Chinese foundation. Our current ratio of Chinese and foreign teachers is 1:1.
             Our team includes professional foreign teachers, overseas returnees, PhDs, Masters, IB examiners, IB evaluation team
             members, including experienced and excellent teachers who have been engaged in IB education for more than ten years.












                                                                                                                  12]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[Our residential and academic programmers

                 allow students to explore boundless possibilities and

                to be inspired to exceed their own expectations.

      13]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[苏国外希雅国际学校

















                                                                                               卓越课程
                                                  04                                  激发创新才能




                                                                                  Excellent Curriculums
                                                                          fulfilling our talent together



                                                      卓越的学术水平是希雅立校之本。希雅培养具有批判性思维的学习
                                                  者，以学习者为中心，激发学生的能动性。学生具有群体思维方式和个人
                                                  感知能力，从而主动在一个支持性和协同性的环境中进行探索和学习，独
                                                  立思考，必然激发创新才能。由创新而自主发现新问题，并解决新问题，
                                                  进而提升领导力。
                                                  Academic excellence is the foundation for the International School of SIA.
                                                  We aim to develop learners with critical thinking skills in a learning-centred
                                                  environment, with respect for students' initiative. Students can explore and
                                                  learn in a more supportive and collaborative environment, and learn to think
                                                  independently,  to  stimulate  innovation.  Through  this,  problems  are
                                                  independently addressed and solved, enhancing leadership.































                                                                                        我们的生活和学术课程
                                                                                               使学生能够探索

                                                                                                  无限的可能性
                                                                                                      受到启发
                                                                                                      超越自我
                                                                                                                  14]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[科学的课程体系

                        SCIENTIFIC CURRICULUM SYSTEM














































      15]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[苏国外希雅国际学校



















                     学生可以在六大学科组丰富的课程中进行个性化、定制化的选择，在拓宽知识面的同时，更能充分
                 发挥自身学科特长，为申请藤校、牛津剑桥及全球TOP30名校打下坚实的学术基础。
                     所有开设的学科，学生可以自由选择学习难度。学生可以根据不同的学科优势，自主选择标阶或高
                 阶的课程学习，这也是IB课程的独到之处。
                     通过本地或全球性话题，学生能够进行跨学科学习，将学习内容与周围的世界关联起来。



                 Students can make individualized and custom choices from the rich depth of courses in the six discipline
                 groups. While broadening their knowledge, they can truly develop their own discipline expertise and lay an
                 academic foundation for applying to Ivy League schools, Oxbridge, and the world's top 30 universities.
                 A unique facet of IB is that for all subjects offered, students can freely choose either standard-level or higher-
                 level courses according to their own abilities.
                 Through studying local and global topics, students work across a number of disciplines, making connections
                 between what they learn and the world around them.








                         组别

                        第一组
                A        母语         中文A                                                    标阶     高阶

                        第二组
                B      第二语言         英语B                                                    标阶     高阶

                        第三组
                C     个人与社会         经济学、心理学、商务管理                                           标阶     高阶
                        第四组
                D        科学         物理、化学、生物、环境系统社会                                        标阶     高阶

                        第五组
                E        数学         数学分析与方法                                                标阶     高阶

                        第六组
                F     艺术或选修         视觉艺术、电影（或第三组、第四组中未选学科）                                 标阶     高阶

                        第七组
                G      中国文化         卓越中国文化、中国历史、中国思想政治、中国地理                                    高阶
                        第八组
                H      国际理解         西方文化、人类文明                                                  高阶








                                                                                                                  16]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[除学科领域外，学生还将钻研IB文凭课程的三大核心课程，即知识论、扩展性论文以及创
                   造力、行动力和服务项目。
                   Apart  from  the  mentioned  subject  areas,  students  will  delve  into  another  three  core  subjects  of  the  IB
                   Diploma, namely Theory of Knowledge, Extended Essay and Projects of Creativity, Activity and Service.











                                      知识论要求学生深入了解知识本身。这是一门哲学学科，旨在让学生提出问题，
                     知识论              深入了解知识的构成方式以及对个人和文化方面的知识偏见进行批判性思维。
                       TOK
                                      Theory  of  Knowledge  gets  students  to  look  deeply  into  knowledge  itself.  It  is  a
                                      philosophical  subject  designed  for  students  to  ask  questions,  look  deeply  at  how
                                      knowledge  is  constructed,  and  think  critically  about  biases  in  knowledge  both
                                      personally and culturally.




                                      拓展论文可以被视为微型论文，在此类论文中，学生可以探索其学科组内感兴趣
                    扩展论文              的领域。EE使学生能够进一步提高研究技能，并在与导师进行的一系列谈话中反
                       EE
                                      思自己的主题。
                                      The extended essay can be considered a mini-thesis in which the student explores an
                                      area of interest within their subject groups, or as an interdisciplinary inquiry across
                                      two study areas of global significance. This essay enables students to further their
                                      research skills as well as reflect on their topic during a series of interviews with a
                                      supervisor.


                                      专为IB文凭课程学生的个人发展而设计。通过一个自我指导的项目，学生必须在
                创造、行动、服务              与创意、体育活动和志愿活动交织的体验之旅中使用问题解决技能、沟通和决策
                       CAS
                                      能力。
                                      CAS is specifically designed for the personal development of IB Diploma students.
                                      Through  a  self-guided  project,  students  must  use  problem-solving  techniques,
                                      communication and decision-making skills in an experiential journey interweaving
                                      with creativity, physical activity, and volunteering.


















      17]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[苏国外希雅国际学校






           严谨的评价方式                     Assessment Policy












                                 占比20%—50%
                           内部评价                                              外部评价
                                                                                      占比50%—80%
                         Internal Assessment                               External Assessment







               语 言 学 科 口 试 、 数 学 学 科 实 际 问 题 的 课 题 研
                                                                           全球统考（每年5月）
               究，科学学科实验报告，以及地理环境学科野
               外考察报告，经济小论文等形式。                                        Universal Exam (May every year)
               Oral assessment in language subjects, research on
               practical  problems  in  mathematics  subjects,
               experimental  reports  in  science  subjects,  field
               investigation  reports  in  geography  and
               environment subjects, mini economic papers, etc.












































                                                                                                                  18]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[我们学校努力为学生提供

                                                              以学生为主导驱动的
                                                              活力四射、参与感强、见解深刻的学习体验。

                                                              Our school strives
                                                              for a dynamic,
                                                              engaging, insightful and fulfilling
                                                              Learning experience

                                                              owned and driven by learners.

                                                              学业优异固然重要，我们也希望学生通过了解全球挑战
                                                              和机遇的本质后，能够培养解决问题的技能，用创新的
                                                              方式找到解决方案。我们将学习视为探究、构建、解
                                                              构，完善对各种概念的理解和对社会的认知。

                                                              Academic excellence is essential, yet we also want our learners to
                                                              thrive today and tomorrow through understanding the nature of
                                                              the  world s  challenges  and  opportunities,  and  to  develop
                                                              problem  solving  skills  to  find  solutions  in  new  and  innovative
                                                              ways.



      19]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[苏国外希雅国际学校






                                                                                            Caring

                   05                                              “ 我 们 以 哈 利 波 特 学 院 为 灵 感 ， 建 立 了 自 己 的


                                                                   House，让我善于交流、懂得关心。”
                                                                    Inspired  by  the  Harry  Potter  Academy,  we  have  built
                                                                   o u r  o w n  H o u s e ,  w h i c h  m a k e s  m e  g o o d  a t
                                                                   communication and caring.




                                                                            Balanced



                                                                   “它给你一个全面的教育。另外，我很享受在希
              终身学习成长                                               雅用IB方式学习的那段时光。”

                                                                   “It  gives  you  a  well-rounded  education  as  opposed  to
            希雅师生如是说                                                the fairly narrow studies of alternatives. Also, I enjoyed
                                                                   my time studying the IB.
             Lifelong Learning of

         SIA Teachers and Students
                                                                                              Open-minded



                                                                    “在IB里，过程和结果都很重要。”
                                                                    “Both processes and results are essential in IB course
                                                                    learning.
 我们学校努力为学生提供
 以学生为主导驱动的          Thinkers
 活力四射、参与感强、见解深刻的学习体验。                                                Resilience

          “这（IB）当然不适合所有人，但其实也没有那么难，但它
          确实让你学到很多技能，会让你接受到不断自我挑战的教                                “三年的高中生活印证了勤奋刻苦是学习与事业成
          育。我觉得这太难以置信了。”                                           功的基础。这是中国人的骄傲与自豪。”
          “It certainly isn't for everyone, and it is tremendously harder    My  high  school  life  has  proved  that  hard  work  is  the
          than I imagined but it does give you so many transferable skills   foundation  of  success  in  study  and  career.  This  is  the
                                                                   pride of Chinese people.
          and it makes you so much better educated. I learned so much it
          is unbelievable.

                                                                             Principled

                              Knowledgeable
                                                                    “在任何情况下，无论是工作还是大学学习，希雅提
                                                                    倡的价值观念、关键能力和必备品格，都是
         “希雅IB   课程老师    教会你如何合理地管理时间，为下一
                                                                    为未来做好准备的重要部分。”
         个阶段的学习做好准备。
                                                                    “Discipline and skills are two vital pieces in regards to
         “It promotes the development of well-rounded individuals.
                                                                    being  prepared  for  the  future  in  any  circumstance,
                                                                    whether it s a job or college.

                                                                                                                  20]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[希雅为基石

                06                                                World-Famous Universities
                                                                     通往世界名校之路

                                                                             SIA the Roadmap to




                    B
                    I  课程经过50年的发展，被全球教育界认可为具有极高学术水准的教育项目， IB学生进入常春藤联盟大
                学的录取率比总录取率高18%。哈佛、耶鲁、普林斯顿等常春藤盟校以及包括牛津、剑桥在内的世界一流大
                学都非常欢迎IB学生申请入读，均视IB文凭为优良的入学资历。希雅提供高质量IB课程，助力中国学生通向
                世界名校。
                After 50 years of development, the IB curriculum is recognized as an educational program with extremely high
                academic standards. The admission rate of IB students entering Ivy League universities is 18% higher than the
                overall  admission  rate.  Ivy  League  schools  such  as  Harvard,  Yale,  and  Princeton,  as  well  as  world-class
                universities including Oxford and Cambridge, all welcome IB students to apply, and all regard the IB diploma as
                an excellent admission qualification.










      21]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[麻省理工学院              剑桥大学              斯坦福大学               牛津大学             哈佛大学












                      宾夕法尼亚大学            普林斯顿大学               耶鲁大学              康奈尔大学             香港大学







                                                                                                                  22]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[2022年IB考试成绩

               RESULTS OF IB EXAMINATION IN 2022








                                          38                           31.8



                                         希雅平均分                          全球平均分















               100%                             40+                                   100%


                   全球前50大学                                                               全球前30专业















































      23]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[苏国外希雅国际学校




                   部分录取成果

                   PARTIAL ADMISSION RESULTS






                                       连续26年
                             No.1      全美“企业管理学”专业排名第1                 美国巴布森学院






                                        No.1       全球“教育学”专业排名第1                 英国伦敦大学学院






                                              No.1        全球“艺术”专业排名第1               英国伦敦艺术大学






                                               No.1        全球“传媒学”专业排名第1               荷兰阿姆斯特丹大学







                                             No.8         全球QS大学排名第8                  英国伦敦大学学院






                                       No.21         全球QS大学排名第21                  香港大学






                             No.28        全球QS大学排名第28                 英国曼彻斯特大学


                                                                                                    ……




                    希雅毕业生将更具国际理解力，他们对在成人社会中的新兴角色有更清晰的了解，能够运用批判性思维
                做出个人决策，能够具有集体意识并且尊重自己和他人。希雅帮助学生与真实世界联结，成为真正的全球公
                民，肩负起领创美好生活的使命。
                SIA graduates have a greater international understanding and a clearer insight into their emerging roles in adult
                society. They are able to use critical thinking to make introspective individual decisions, as well as having a
                community awareness and respect for themselves and others. SIA helps students connect seamlessly with society
                and become true global citizens. They are shouldering the mission of leading a better life.



                                                                                                                  24]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[07









         专业升学团队


         打造专属升学方案

         Professional Counsellors
         Create Exclusive Admission Scheme



































































      25]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[苏国外希雅国际学校





                               A               提供专业选课建议              Prefessional advice for subject choice


                            学生在进入苏国外希雅国际学校后，升学辅导老师为他/她设计个性化成长方案。在综合考虑学生的
                        基础学业水平、个人发展意向、家庭情况等因素后，为学生建议最适合的选课。
                        Based on students  academic capabilities, interests, career ideas and family backgrounds, counsellors will give
                        substantial guidance on curriculum decisions, plus academic and career development activities.





                               B               尊重个性差异            Respect for students' diversity


                            升学辅导老师会配合任课老师，在遵循教育、人才成长规律的基础上，创新教育教学的方式方法，探
                        索多样的培养方式，关注学生不同特点，尊重个性差异，发展、发现每位学生的优势和潜能，引导他们找
                        到自己未来发展的方向，不断挑战自我。
                        The counsellors, work closely with teachers, to cultivate the students  inner capabilities. The school will also
                        offer personalised plans to meet the student s individual needs and requirements.
































                               C               个性化升学方案             Best-fit application plan


                            学校升学辅导团队在英国、美国、加拿大等国的大学申请方面拥有十分丰富的经验。他们为学生们合
                        理安排学习、标准化考试、学术竞赛、课外活动等，帮助学生满足大学申请条件。根据学生的特长、兴趣
                        提供对大学专业选择上的帮助，并协助学生选择申请适合自己的大学。
                        SIA counsellors have a rich data pool and experiences with regard to the process of admission applications to
                        universities/colleges  in  North  America,  the  UK,  and  the  rest  of  the  World.  Specifically,  SIA  will  make
                        appropriate  arrangements  for  the  students,  regarding  college-entry  tests,  extracurricular  activities,  and
                        organising relevant timeslots. Lastly, SIA will suggest the best-choice universities/colleges candidates to the
                        students and help them to successfully complete the application.






                                                                                                                  26]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[苏国外希雅国际学校












                       D               全球学术竞赛 Support for global competitions


                    升学辅导老师会根据学生专业申请的意向，给出匹配的全球学术竞赛建议。学生在校即可进行学术竞
                赛的营地补习，学科老师全力助力学生申请世界名校。希雅也是全球众多学术竞赛的考点，学生在校即可
                参 加 美 国 数 学 竞 赛 （A M C ） 、英 国 数 学 竞 赛 （B M O ） 、美 国 物 理 竞 赛 （B M O ） 、英 国 物 理 竞 赛
                （BPhO）、英国化学竞赛（UKChO）、加拿大化学竞赛（CCC）、澳大利亚生物竞赛（ASOB）。
                SIA counsellors will make suggestions for global academic competitions according to the intentions of the
                students  with  regard  to  the  major  they  are  applying  for.  Students  can  take  camp  tutoring  for  academic
                competitions at school, and subject teachers help students apply for world-renowned schools at every step.
                Our school is also the test centre for many academic competitions around the world. Students can participate
                in  the  American  Mathematics  Competition  (AMC),  the  British  Mathematical  Competition  (BMO),  the
                American Physics Competition (BMO), the British Physics Competition (BPhO), and the British Chemistry
                Competition (UKChO)., Canadian Chemistry Competition (CCC), Australian Biology Competition (ASOB).































                       E               冲刺顶级名校            Sprint for dream schools


                    对于申请英国牛剑等G5院校、美国藤校或其他世界顶尖名校的学生进行专属方案定制，通过学术成
                绩、国际竞赛、学术课题研究和论文、实习、推荐信、牛剑营等多维度完善学生申请方案。

                Exclusive program customization for students applying for the G5 super elite such as Oxbridge in the UK, and
                Ivy  League  schools  in  the  United  States  or  other  top  universities  in  the  world.  To  perfect  the  student
                application program through academic performance training, international competitions, academic research
                and papers, internships, letters of recommendation, and Oxbridge camps, etc.








      27]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[28]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[08                                                      多维关怀







                                                          助力学生成长

                                                    Multi-Dimensional Care

                                                to Help Students in Growth










                 专职导师 Professional supervisors


                   学校配备了班级发展管理小组、生活导师团队。班主任不仅仅关注学生的学业发展，还是学生们的情感顾
               问，关注学生情绪，排解学生困惑；生活导师在照顾学生日常饮食起居的同时，帮助学生培养自理能力、生活
               习惯、文明礼仪等。
               The school is equipped with a student management and dorm supervisors  team. The homeroom teacher not only
               pays  attention  to  the  academic  performance  of  the  students,  but  also  serves  as  an  emotional  advisor  to  the
               students, taking care of and dealing with their psychological and emotional problems. The dorm supervisors will
               help to cultivate students  self-care ability, healthy living habits, civilized etiquette, etc. while taking care of the
               students' daily diet and daily life.










                专业医疗团队           Professional medical team



               学校专业医疗团队为每一名学生提供最人                   The school's professional medical team provides every student with
               性化的安全保障：                             the best protection:
                 预防为主、防治结合
                                                      Prevention first, with a combination of prevention and treatment
                 7X24小时值班
                 提供规范的全程优质医疗服务                        24x7 care
                                                      Provide standardized full-course high-quality medical services













      29]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[苏国外希雅国际学校
































































                  专职心理导师            Professional Psychological Mentor



                  学校设有心理咨询中心，配备专业心理老师，为学生提供咨询服务，指导自我调节、释放心理压力、解决
              心理困惑和矛盾。更重要的是，学校鼓励学生做自己情绪的管理者，学会调整心态、解决心理问题。

              The psychology health centre in SIA provides professional psychological services to all students — instructing
              students to learn self-control methods, releasing psychological pressure and solving psychological conflicts. In
              addition, the students have opportunities to attend psychological health courses which call for students  awareness
              for their psychological health. More importantly, the school works hard to encourage each student to manage their
              own psychological well-being.










                                                                                                                  30]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[09                                                     跨世纪老牌名校

                                                                                        森林氧吧


                                                             Cross-century brand school with
                                                                            Natural forest setting



                 苏国外占地面积11万㎡，总建筑面积约11万㎡，配有多功能教室、IB科学实验室、图书馆、多功能
             表演艺术中心、户外双操场（400米跑道、250米跑道）、多功能体育场地（篮球、排球、足球、羽毛
             球、乒乓球、美式橄榄球）、户外游泳池、信息计算机中心、艺术室、健身馆、舞蹈房等硬件设施。
                 苏国外师资力量雄厚，包括人民教育家、全国模范教师、省333人才、正高级、特级教师等数十名
             教育教学管理高层次人才。专家领衔、生源优秀、学术氛围浓厚的跨世纪老牌名校，为国际项目的高端
             品质提供了坚实保障。
             The 110000㎡ campus holds a variety of facilities-including multi-functional rooms, science labs, playgrounds, track
             fields, swimming pool, American football court, IT center, art studio, dance studio, and theater, etc.
             SIFLS has abundant faculty and expert resources, including national model teachers, provincial 333 talents, senior
             teachers, provincial special-class teachers and many senior management experts on teaching. Experts led, excellent
             students  and  strong  academic  atmosphere  have  provided  a  solid  guarantee  for  the  high  quality  of  international
             programs in the cross-century brand school.




















































      31]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[苏国外希雅国际学校






                       安保系统 Security system
                      学校建立了完善的安保系统，实行24小时值班巡逻，校园监控全覆盖，包括包括教室、
                  实验室、公寓、操场、健身房等所有学习和活动的场所，并与公安局110中心联动，时刻守护
                  校园安全。

                  The  campus  is  under  24-hour  monitoring.  The  school  security  system  is  wired  to  the  local
                  police station. The security staff, along with a school leader, keep duty all day every day.

































                                                       餐饮服务团队由高级厨师、营养师组成，学校特别重视饮
                                                   食安全和卫生，采用非转基因食用油、东北五常有机大米，蔬
                                                   果每日新鲜采购，所有食材均可追溯生产地。每日餐饮都按健
                                                   康饮食标准和现代营养学的要求进行搭配。
                          餐饮服务                     The  school  provides  the  students  with  safe,  nutritious,  and
                          Catering services        delicious  food.  All  raw  materials  are  fresh,  organic,  and  non-
                                                   genetically  modified.  The  catering  recipes  are  carefully  created
                                                   for breakfast, lunch, and dinner.






                       学生住宿 Boarding Dormitory
                      学生公寓2-4人一间，恒温恒湿、节能微
                  排，卫生间、淋浴室、衣柜、洗衣机等设备齐
                  全，为学生提供舒适、安全的生活环境。
                  Each  dorm  can  provide  4  students  with
                  comfortable  boarding  facilities-furniture,  an  air
                  conditioning  system,  a  bathroom  with  shower,
                  and laundry service, etc.





                                                                                                                  32]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[招生计划
                             Enrollment Plan


                                                     招生计划                 学费

                               高一（F P）                25人/班             21万元/年

                               高二（DP）                 25人/班             21万元/年
                               九年级（PFP）               20人/班             8.8万元/年







                             入学标准

                             Entrance Criteria
                             招收九年级、高一、高二的适龄学生；
                             申请高一（FP）的学生在申请时应至少在九年级或高一就读；
                             申请高二（DP）的学生在申请时应至少在高一或高二就读。







      33]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[苏国外希雅国际学校









                           奖学金政策
                           Scholarship Programme




                              希雅
                             特别奖                          一次性奖励10万







                          一等                二等                 三等
                                                                                    入学
                                                31.5万                              奖学金
                             63万                 减免1/2            21万
                               全免                                 减免1/3






                              名校
                             升学奖               30万               15万               10万
                                              一等升学奖             二等升学奖             三等升学奖













































                                                                                                                  34]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[加入我们





                                          纳新融变  筑梦未来


                                  Inspiring learners to become architects of their future



































                       苏国外希雅国际学校

            地 址          江苏省苏州市相城大道100号
                         100 Xiangcheng Ave, Suzhou
            网 址          www.sia-edu.cn
            电 话          0512-65490316；65490317
                                                                       服务号             小程序            企业微信]]></page></pages></Search>